Alright, go to search bar type glue.
Click on AWS glue, go
to ETL Jobs right on the left hand side.
Click on notebook, start fresh.
Choose the role you already have in the real world.
This will be going to you by the team members.
Create notebook. Next, open your VS code.
Go to the notebook app provided.
Put that in the folder
that we code is referencing currently.
So if you look here, I have put the
notebook right here in this folder, which is
what is open here in yes code.
So can I get the file name?
You're gonna write, click and copy.
Go back to glue, click here. Remove what you have.
What do you see there? Right click, paste that and enter.
And then you see the red thing going on here.
Go there, scroll down. It's already removed by the way.
And you can go back to notebook.
And then let's go back to the VS code.
Scroll down, we're gonna copy this entire cell.
I'm gonna copy, click on the cell and right click here.
Copy cell, right click on this cell here.
Control a delete and right click.
And after delete you control V or there.
So you were able to copy the code from your
via code and then you will run this cell.
So we'll go here on top, click here, run this.
It is now gonna create the session spark session.
Meanwhile, we'll delete the next cells that we don't need.
We'll just go here, click on this knife symbol,
we'll click on deleting all of them one by one.
It's gone. We are waiting for the session
to get created right now.
Meanwhile, we'll go back to the V code, go
to the next cell, click here.
And again, three dots here.
Copy cell, go back to notebook.
So what did the first cell do?
We are trying to get this park code run with the help
of G one X worker type.
And we need three workers
and we are initializing this spark session.
It's all done. Now we see the
spark session has been created.
So we are gonna go to this plus symbol
here on this notebook.
We have a new cell and now we're gonna
just uh, do control V.
So what does this code do?
Okay, this code
initially just assign the variables, their values.
Okay, the bucket, the curated path
where the curated data is, where the zone path is, right?
Where the zone data look up, look up file is
and then the aggregated path
where we wanna store the aggregated data.
And then we wanna just test this code only for
the February, 2024.
Only for now. So this essentially is
to just set the variables.
So we'll just run it now to run this we,
we have anyway chosen this.
It's shows blue here, we'll just run this
cell and this shows busy.
Yeah, it's all good. Now we have the output here as well.
We'll go back to the via code. Scroll down.
Now what is the first step?
Step is to load the January, 2024 data,
which is curated and through
The zone lookup file.
So we'll just click on this particular cell
and then copy the cell here.
Go back to notebook here we're gonna paste it.
Okay, if you look at the code,
we are simply loading the curated data for Jan 2024.
We are also reading the zone lookup file. Okay?
And then we're taking a look at the schemas
and the sample data as well.
We'll run this. Alright, so this is all loaded.
We see we have 90 million records for Jan 2025.
We also have loaded the zone lookup table.
So the information is right here, the sample data.
Now we loaded the zone lookup table
because as mentioned here, the zone names the pickup,
borrow, pick up zone, drop of borrow, drop
of zone are de normalized in aggregated layer
by joining the zone table during EDL.
So we need zone table now.
So the next step will actually enrich the data we have
with the appropriate the pickup and drop locations.
We'll go back to the VS code and go to step two.
Now create enrich dataset with Azure information.
So we'll just copy this and go back to our notebook,
create one more cell here.
We already have a cell. We'll just paste that
and we'll run it.
And if we take a look at the code here,
we are now joining the curated data set with the zone table.
Okay, we have a zone table here.
We have Allst data pickup zone and drop of zone.
And we are joining to the same table
through two data frames.
Okay? We essentially,
we have only asked it when we join them, we'll be able
to get the exact locations
and we join them based on the location id.
Okay, now this pickup location ID
and drop off location id, these two r and d curated ones
and we join them with the location ID fields
in the pickup zone table.
Okay? Again, join is a pretty popular function, uh,
in data engineering and I hope, uh, you have gone
through my SQL skill booster
and PI box skill booster
where these things are already covered.
So if you see after joining them,
you are selecting the columns from the curated field,
the data frame, and then you also enrich by
selecting the fields from the zone lookup table.
This way. So we have the data ready now,
so it does show the sample and this data, right?
You get the exact location manager
and Bronx, all of that instead of just the
location IDs, in fact.
So the next step will be to create the aggregation tables
as we already saw and discussed before.
So we'll create this table one, two,
and three in the next step.